Hello! Welcome to the long-awaited bounty vlog
number one about my challenge of 100 hours of
hunting on a public program from Hackerone. In
this video, I will show you what program was that,
how did I approach it, what did I report and,
finally, how much I earned. I will also tell you
where to find my methodology and my notes. Enjoy!
For those of you who didn't watch the bounty
vlog number 0, I will just briefly talk about my
background. So for three years I was a pentester
and I would say I have quite solid background in
web security. However, when it came to bug bounty,
I was jumping from one program to another
and I wasn't finding many bugs. I only had
one monetary reward which is also covered
in a video on this channel. So up until now,
I wasn't a very successful bughunter. When I was
recording a podcast with David Shutz, he said
many smart things but one of them was that when he
understands the flow, the bugs come naturally. And
I decided to test on myself if what's being said
in my podcast works for me or not. So I decided
to spend 100 hours on a bug bounty program. But
importantly I didn't start it with attitude to
find bugs. I started it with only wanting to
understand different flows in the application,
hoping that the bugs will come naturally to me
like they do to David. The rules were also that
I don't want to do any subdomain enumeration or
directory brute force because I just wanted to
test if I have to do this or not. The program I
chose was Stripe. It's a payment provider that I
use myself to handle payments for BBRE Premium.
It's mostly an API with which we, as sellers,
integrate. But there's also a dashboard and
the scope also includes many other assets.
My first session on Stripe was 3,5 hours and
I focused on the flow that BBRE subscribers go
through when subscribing to my paid newsletter.
And after this time, I understood what are the
requests, what are the parameters and so on but I
had no vulnerability. After that, I had to spend
a few days on creating a video so I didn't
hack. But I consciously, throughout the day,
thought about what could I do with this flow.
And the idea that came to my mind was to test
archived prices. Because at first, I was selling
BBRE Premium for $48 and after a week, I archived
that old price and created a new of $79. So
if someone would be able to use the old price,
it would be saving of $31 so it's quite a good
impact. So I tried to use the old checkout link
but it didn't work. Instead, I started the flow
with the new link but in the middle of the flow,
I changed back to the previous one and all of
a sudden, I was able to purchase BBRE Premium
for $48. So I filed a report. It was my first
report on Hackerone since about two years so it
was an insane time and I had, what STOK calls, a
bug fever. I even turned on mobile notifications
for gmail in my phone to not miss any updates. In
general, it was a terrible experience because I
was getting loads of notifications and every time
something on gmail popped up, my heart started
beating quicker. The bug was triaged as medium
which was very fair. For medium on api.stripe.com,
the range is $1,000 - $5,000. Unfortunately, I was
at the bottom of the range but I was still very
happy with this bounty. Especially considering
how much time I spent. Then, after the next hours,
I was understanding more and more flows of Stripe
but I didn't have any bugs. So I wanted to look
elsewhere. In scope of bug bounty program there
are also repositories on Stripe account on GitHub.
Among others, there are SDKs to communicate with
Stripe API from different programming languages or
from the terminal. I found a bug there after about
two days of hunting. It was very hard to actually
exploit but it was a clear bug so I decided to
report it, even though I wasn't sure if they will
accept it or not. This one is not disclosed so I
can't really tell you more about it. But if you
are a member of BBRE Premium, you actually know
what method did I use to find this bug because
I can't tell you "this is the tool that I used
to find this bug" because it's confidential but
I can easily tell you, among tens and hundreds
of other tips in BBRE Premium, "this is how to
use this tool" and I know that it's the method
to exploit this bug but you don't know this
but if you read everything carefully, you know the
methods that I use. So this is what I do on BBRE
Premium. So read everything carefully and after
a few months, maybe after disclosure, you will
realize that the article you read half a year ago
was the method that I used to exploit this bug.
Coming back to the bug, it was rewarded $500
as a low which I agree with, which was on the
other hand, top of the range for this asset. So at
this point things were looking really really good,
much better than I expected because after about
24 hours of hunting, I earned $1600 with retests.
But then came the hardest part. I wasn't finding
anything throughout the next hours. I was spending
most of my time on stripe.com but I also looked
at other assets. After about 45 hours, I was
seriously considering ending the experiment after
50 hours, but I stuck with it. After 60 hours, I
was pretty much sure I won't find anything anymore
but I just wanted to complete that for the video.
I was really unmotivated and there was a lot of
procrastination which is one of the reasons why
it took me so long to complete this 100 hours.
But then, after 82 hours, I found another bug
which later turned out to be my biggest payout.
It was another open source application from
GitHub and it's also pending disclosure
so I can't tell you more details about it.
It was classified as low with which I don't
quite agree but apart from $500 of base payout
I also got $1,000 of bonus because they were
happy that I'm attacking this particular asset,
for a total of $1,500. Most of the remaining time
I spent trying to find a bypass for this last
vulnerability but I didn't find anything. So after
100 hours the final result is $3,100. But is it
really final? Maybe yes but maybe not. Because the
second bug - they tried to fix it but they didn't.
And it wasn't even a bypass - the original
proof of concept I presented still worked
after the attempt to fix it. So I mentioned
it in a retest, I mentioned it in comments
but there was no action from their side. So after
exactly 90 days from the original submission,
I decided to report it again to maybe get the
same bounty twice. And as I said previously,
if they would close it as informational the first
time around, I wouldn't object. But for - me maybe
my understanding is wrong, you can write
in comments what do you think about it,
when you triage, pay and resolve the report
you kinda commit to fixing it. So the second
report was closed as duplicate but I opened
mediation and I don't know yet how it will end.
And another thing is that for this video, I
am also giving you my notes - more about it
later. But before disclosing them, I wanted
to contact Stripe if they are okay with me
publishing this information because among typical
notes, there were also things that I call "quirks
or potential vulnerabilities" which weren't risky
enough for me to report it but I hoped that maybe
I will be able to chain them one day. For example,
there was a patg traversal in stripe-cli or two
XSSes without content security policy bypass.
All they told me back is that if I disclose
something that turns out to be a vulnerability,
then I will not be paid for it. It didn't change
anything because if I wanted to submit any
of this before I would do it long time ago.
But one useful thing they told me is that they do
accept XSSes without CSP bypass. And I had two of
them. They were on in-scope domain but they were
really hard to actually exploit to do something
malicious. So I didn't really want to report
this but I decided that I report one of them
and if they accept this, I will consider reporting
the second one. But I don't think they will accept
this submission. I can already tell you that there
will be a second part of this bounty vlog. After
those reports are closed, I will tell you
more about them, I will show you my notes
and I will answer your questions you can submit
them in the comments down below. But the second
part will be a live stream on YouTube so you will
be also able to ask me questions in the real time
on the chat. But don't ask me when will
it be because it doesn't depend on me.
So let's think about if this $3,100 is a lot or
not. But before doing, that let's clear up what
does the 100 hours number mean for me. Because
many of you probably think that it's 8 hour
work day times 12.5. So two and a half weeks of
full-time work. But it's not. Instead, I log only
the real time of working and from a typical eight
hour work day, excluding breaks, useless meetings,
responding to emails, procrastination and so on,
you probably get 5-6 hours on a good day. For me,
100 hours means about a month. Of course, I also
do videos, the newsletter and so on, and so on.
So for me it was spread across three months but
if I was only doing bug bounty, it would take
one month to complete 100 hours of hunting. Is it
as much as I would earn as a pentester? No, not
even in Poland. But I'm still very happy with this
number because at the beginning, I didn't believe
this experiment at all. I thought I will find
nothing. So this number, on the other hand, is
something that I can easily live for for a month
in Kraków. Some of the factors that motivated me
to quit my job is that I'm young, I don't have
kids, debts and inflation of living standards
hasn't hit me badly, at least not yet. So I don't
spend that much. On the other hand, Stripe is a
well-paying program and those are only two lows
and one medium when you think about it. There
are a lot of what-ifs because those bugs had the
impact but also there were a lot of prerequisites
for the attacks to be possible. So if some of
those prerequisites were not there or maybe if I
would get the middle of the range with the medium
risk bug, the payout would be much higher. And
also, with only those three submissions, I made
it to top 7 on the leaderboard and in hacktivity,
you can see that no one apart from me in this
time submitted more than one report to Stripe.
The important takeaway for me is the type of
assets that I attack. Because out of those
100 hours I spent majority - maybe 60 hours - on
Stripe.com and I only found one bug after 4 hours
and then nothing after 56 hours. I had many
potential bugs, something that I could chain
and I hope that magically, something that I found
after 10 hours, I will be able to chain or turn
into a bug after 50 hours with something else.
But this moment never came. It taught me that even
though Stripe is very big, it's not as complex
as, let's say Google. Because, for example,
when you have one YouTube video, you can watch
it on YouTube, you can watch it on YouTube TV,
you can see it from YouTube studio and then you
can also access it from Google ads. On Stripe,
I found very few places where the same resource
was modified from different components, from
different parts of the application and I think
it made hunting harder. And, of course, there is
no question about the fact that I simply missed
a lot of bugs, as we all do. On the other hand,
when I look at the time invested into open source
assets, it was well worth it and I think in the
future, I should focus more on that. Now if you
believe you will find bugs that I missed or you
just want to see how I organize my notes, check
out my whole Notion page with notes that I took
throughout this 100 hours. Of course, there are
some confidential parts that I had to redact but
majority is still there. You can get them if
you sign up for BBRE newsletter but I promise
you you won't regret this. The link is in the card
right now or in the description. If you want to go
even a step further and learn with me in BBRE
Premium, check out premium.bugbountyxplained.com.
I think it will be quite interesting after
these bugs get disclosed, I will be able
to point you that the tip that led to this bug
was published in this issue of the newsletter,
a few months earlier. For the next episode
I will go more into the source code analysis
because I will spend 100 hours on Elastic. To not
miss that episode, subscribe to the channel and
like this video so YouTube recommends my
videos to you and also to other hackers
that will find it helpful. For now
thank you for watching and goodbye!